# CV - Azer Safarov

## **Personal Details**

Full name: Azer Safarov Date of birth: 23.07.1990

Address: Azerbaijan, Baku, District 6

Mobile: +994 55 339 22 43

Email: gramulos@gmail.com

Website: http://azersafarov.com

#### **Education**

Azerbaijan, Baku – Baku State University BSc Computer Science (2007 – 2011)

Azerbaijan, Baku – Baku State University

MSc Computer Science (2012 – 2015)

#### **About me**

I am a Frontend developer with big experience of UX/UI management. I have a love of clean, modern frameworks, and I have lots of experience with different frameworks and architectures. I am a highly motivated, self-driven developer. Mainly I have focused on client side on JavaScript, HTML/CSS. I always strive to extend my skills in programming and hone existing ones by self-study.

# **Experience**

# Full Stack Developer at Data Processing Center of Ministry of Communications and High Technologies, Azerbaijan

October 2013 - Present

- Development and maintenance of existing PKI system.
- Responsible for implementation and design of new products and web applications in the organization.
- Client & Server side development using the latest frameworks and technologies (JavaScript, Node.JS, ASP Web API, AngularJS, React.JS)
- Working in Agile environment.
- Working with Web Services (REST & SOAP), Certificates, Cryptographic API's, Smart Cards,

#### Cofounder and leading software designer at ACCODERS LLC, Azerbaijan

October 2012 - October 2015

- Developing of web sites and services.
- UI/UX management.
- Working with startup projects.

# CA Administrator at Data Processing Center of Ministry of Communications and High Technologies, Azerbaijan

October 2012 – October 2013

- Maintenance of existing PKI system.
- Administration of databases.

# Senior laboratory at Institute of Information Technology, National Academy of Sciences, Azerbaijan

April 2010 - October 2010

• Support and maintenance of existing 'EPrints' system



# **Projects**

# **Epsilon Groups brand site (at Epsilon Groups LLC)**

EPSILON GROUPS provides systems and services in the fields of intelligent systems, robotic vehicles (including unmanned ground, air, and sea vehicles), robotics and automation, weapons systems, intelligent control systems, intelligent transportation systems, intelligent manufacturing, and other advanced technology for government, industry, and not-for-profit clients.

Technologies & frameworks: React.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

http://epsilongroups.com/

# **Lucky Store (at Epsilon Groups LLC)**

Lottery system for mobile operators. Users can buy ticket to participate in a lottery. The winner win the prize (IPhone, MacBook, IPad, etc.). User can subscribe to the service. Every user operation done via sending SMS. System can have different lotteries played in parallel. The system integrates with mobile operator billing system and SMS Center (to receive and send SMS).

Technologies & frameworks: React.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Adobe Photoshop

# eGov Payment (at Data Processing Center - MCHT)

eGov Payment is a web application where the citizen can pay their bills like electricity, water bill, mortgage, telephone bill, etc.

**Technologies & frameworks:** Angular.js, IIS, ASP.NET Web API, MS SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

https://www.e-gov.az/az/services/readwidenew/3425/

### **Mobile Signature (at Data Processing Center - MCHT)**

Mobile Signature is mobile application for digitally sign files. The program is only works with certificates produced by the Certificate Center of Azerbaijan and supports Gemalto and Siemens cards. The program is written in Java for Android platform. It will be soon available in Google Play and will be written to IOS platform. The program also used in order to login into the Azerbaijan E-Government portal via the Smart Card and a Mobile Device.

Technologies & frameworks: Java, XML, CSS, Adobe Photoshop

# **Online Signer (at Data Processing Center - MCHT)**

Java applet for digital signing, verifying and opening signed files from web browser. The program written in Java and communicates with Smart Cards, middle-wares, uses different Cryptographic API's for Digital Signature.

Technologies & frameworks: Java, Spring

http://e-imza.az/websigner.php?lang=en

#### Military Shooting Simulator (at ACCODERS LLC)

Virtual trainer is assigned to train people for the purpose of enhancing their military skills and musketry. Designing of user interface.

**Technologies & frameworks:** Adobe Photoshop

http://epsilongroups.com/#/software/vt

# ESignature brand site (at Data Processing Center - MCHT)

ESignature brand web site of National Certificate Service Center of Data Processing Center of MCHT.

Technologies & frameworks: PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

http://e-imza.az/index.php?lang=en

#### **Certifications**

**MS: Programming in C#** - Microsoft, License F252-8054 *April 2015* 

MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional - Microsoft, License F252-8056

April 2015

#### Courses

#### **Pluralsight**

- Front End Web Development: Get Started (by Joe Eames)
- JavaScript the Good Parts (by Douglas Crockford)

# **Udemy**

- Build Web Apps with React JS and Flux (by Stephen Grider)
- Modern React with Redux (by Stephen Grider)
- JavaScript: Understanding the Weird Parts (by Anthony Alicea)

#### **Egghead**

Getting Started with Redux (by Dan Abramov)

#### **Skills**

**Graphic editors:** Adobe Photoshop, Corel DRAW

**Based Knowledge:** OOP, SOLID, TDD, Multithreading, Scrum Methodology

**Programming Languages:** JavaScript, C#, Java

Web Development: Node.JS, React, Redux, Flux, AngularJS, ASP.NET Web API,

HTML5, CSS3, LESS, SASS, Bootstrap, Material UI

**SQL Servers:** Microsoft SQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Mobile Development: Android

Web Servers: Apache, IIS

**Source Controls:** Git, Team Foundation Server

Other Technologies: Spring, Windows Form

**OS Systems:** Windows, OS X

**Development Environments:** IntelliJ, Visual Studio, Sublime Text, Atom

### Languages

**English:** Professional working proficiency **Azerbaijani:** Native or bilingual proficiency

Russian: Native or bilingual proficiency Turkish: Limited working proficiency

**German:** Elementary proficiency